OLUWABUKOLA AJIKE FASAN

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Royal Garden Estate, Ajah, Lagos State, Nigeria. 08080110323 oluwabukola.fasan@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I'm a skilled frontend developer, creating user-friendly, responsive web apps. I'm driven by a passion for clean, efficient interfaces, keeping up with the latest tech, ensuring our development follows agile principles and working collaboratively to deliver engaging user experiences.

EXPERIENCE

Startup Hive, Lagos State, Nigeria (Remote) - Frontend Developer

January 2024 - Present

- Transformed UI/UX designs into dynamic code using Next.js, Tailwind CSS, Typescript, and Shadon UI, crafting visually appealing and responsive interfaces.
- Led the optimization of frontend performance, using best practices to enhance page load times
- Collaborated with full-stack developers, specialising in frontend development, database management, and testing.

Sabi Programmers, Ondo State, Nigeria - Frontend Developer

July 2023 - December 2023

- Independently executed UI/UX designs into actual codes using HTML, Tailwind, JavaScript, and React.
- Engineered reusable code components and robust systems, optimizing efficiency and scalability.
- Played a critical role in crafting web app frontends for seamless user interaction.
- Collaborated with product designers, backend developers and project managers.

EDUCATION

Federal University Oye- Ekiti, Ekiti State

- B.Sc in Computer Science November 2015 - January 2020 Second Class Upper Division- 4.39/5.0

TECH STACK

HTML, CSS, Tailwind CSS, JavaScript, Typescript, React, Next, Jest, Bootstrap, Appwrite, PHP, Kotlin

TOOLS

Figma, Vscode, Git, Github, Zoho, Microsoft Team, Android Studio

LINKS

Github Twitter Portfolio

OTHER INTEREST

Node.js, Java, Mysql

Onract Limited, Manchester, England, United Kingdom (Remote) - *UI/UX Designer*

December 2022- December 2023

- Developed intuitive UI mockups and prototypes effectively communicated the functionality and visual aspects of websites.
- Collaborated closely with development teams to ensure the successful implementation of design concepts, providing ongoing support and guidance throughout the project lifecycle.
- Maintained and updated design documentation, including style guides and design specifications, to ensure consistency and alignment with project goals.

Stutern, Lagos, Nigeria (Remote) - Frontend Developer Intern

June 2022 - July 2023

- Implemented six new user-facing features utilising technologies such as React, Redux, Tailwind, and Sass, enhancing website functionality and user experience.
- Conducted regular maintenance and enhancements on websites, ensuring optimal performance and usability.
- Contributed to a mini project and collaborated with cross-functional teams, including UI/UX designers and backend developers, on the Citrone redesign fostering teamwork and innovation.

Zuri Inc-Ingressive for Good, Africa. (Remote) - Product Designer Intern

March 2022 - May 2022

- Designed a mobile management system for efficient task organisation, addressing logistical challenges within the industry.
- Conducted comprehensive user research in the logistics sector, informing design decisions and enhancing user experiences.
- Collaborated with a team to develop an authentication codes library, contributing to secure access protocols for digital platforms.

Rapidlink technologies, Ekiti State (Remote)-Web Developer

January 2021 - August 2021

- Led the conceptualization and execution of innovative web solutions, aligning with project requirements and client needs.
- Developed and deployed projects using HTML,CSS, and Javascript.
- Stayed updated on emerging web technologie and industry trends, incorporating best practices to enhance project outcomes.

CERTIFICATION

Software Development (Front-end Development)

Stutern, Lagos State. 2022-2023

React Basics

Meta, Coursera 2023

Mobile App Development

Women Techsters Program, Tech4Dev, Lagos State. 2022-2023

Introduction to Android Mobile Application Development

Meta, Coursera 2022

Certificate of Completion (Product Design)

Zuri Inc., Lagos State. 2022

Certificate in Introduction to UI/UX

Geneza School of design, Lagos State. 2022